One strategy that is often used in hybrid approaches for
挙動分類のハイブリッド手法でよく使用される戦略の 1 つが
behavior classification is to combine a classifier with a filter.
分類器とフィルターを結合させる方法です
We will show why.
理由を説明します
For now we will introduce a simple behavior classifier, Naive Bayes.
簡単な挙動分類器 ナイーブベイズを紹介します
Let's walk through how Naive Bayes works by using an example.
例を使ってナイーブベイズの動作について見ていくことにします
We are going to reason on gender using
性別を推論します
statistics of two feature variables; height and weight.
2 種類の特徴変数 高さと重さを使用します
As an output we want the probability that
確率を出力させます
a person is male or female given their height or weight.
その人の身長と体重で男性か女性かを判断します
In a Naive Bayes classifier,
ナイーブベイズ分類器では
the probability of being male given height and weight is
身長と体重で男性と判断される確率は
just the probability of the height given male times the probability of
[男性と判断される身長の確率] x
that weight given male multiplied by the prior probability of being male something
[男性と判断されるその体重の確率] x
close to point five divided by
[前回に男性と判断された確率 (0.5 に近い)] ÷
the probability of the height and weight in the overall population.
[全体人口の身長と体重] の確率になります
The reason why this algorithm is called Naive Bayes is
このアルゴリズムがナイーブベイズと呼ばれる理由は
that it assumes that all features contribute independently.
アルゴリズムではすべての特徴は単独で関係性がないと仮定されるためです
And while in reality there is correlation between height and weight in people.
一方 現実的には人の身長と体重には相関関係がありますが
In practice the independence assumption often winds up working.
実際 最終的には関係性がないと仮定しても適切な結果が得られます
The equation about can be simplified.
この方程式は単純化できます
This term will affect both probabilities male and female in the same way.
この項は 男性と女性の確立に同じように影響します
It is just a normalization factor.
単なる正規化因子です
This means we can first compute this part of the equation
つまり 男性でも女性でも 方程式のこの部分を先に計算
both for male and female and then compute the final probability
することができます 次に身長と体重で
of male given height and rate and probability of female
男性と判断される最終確率 身長と体重で
given height male by normalizing them to make them sum to one.
女性と判断される最終確率を計算し それを正規化してひとつに合計します
The problem is all about finding these terms.
問題はこれらの項を見つけることです
Often, we can assume it goes in distribution for the feature variables.
多くの場合 特徴変数の分布に入ると仮定できます
If you make this assumption the algorithm is then called Gaussian Naive Bayes.
この仮定を行った場合 アルゴリズムはガウスナイーブベイズと呼ばれます
So in practice, implementing a good Gaussian Naive Bayes classifier is all about one,
実際に 適切なガウスナイーブベイズ分類器を実装する場合は 次の点に注意してください
selecting the correct feature variables for the classification problem.
1 分類の問題に正しい特徴変数を選択すること
This is vary can use some human intuition combined with
これは状況により異なるため 人の直感と
feature selection algorithms to anticipate what
特徴選択アルゴリズムを組み合わせて
factors are relevant for a given classification situation.
分類状況に適した因数を予測します
I call her for example would not be very useful in predicting gender.
性別の予測にはあまり便利とは言えないでしょう
And two identifying some good means and variances for different classes.
2 それぞれのクラスに適した分散と平均を見つけること
And we can either guess these numbers or we can look at lots of data to learn them.
これらの数字は推測するか 多くのデータから学び取ることができます
For example, if you have access to lots of data
たとえば 運転者の交差点での操作に関する大量のデータがあり
about how drivers handle intersections and if you define
運転者の緊張を示す適切な特徴
some good features which indicating tension's of drivers you could use
がわかっている場合 ナイーブベイズを使用して
Naive Bayes to compute the probability of each behavior at each time step.
各時間ステップでのそれぞれの動作の確率を計算することができます
For the trajectory prediction part.
トラジェクトリー予測の部分では
You could use one of the following models we talked about earlier.
先ほど説明した次のモデルのいずれかを使用できます